Guide to the E. Virginia Barnett Postcards Collection
University of Houston Libraries
E. Virginia Barnett Postcards Collection
undated
1978-001
Barnett, E. Virginia
0.50 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains eighty-eight vintage postcards collected by E. Virginia Barnett. The collection includes materials from Arkansas, California, Illinois, New Jersey, New York, Texas, Virginia, Oregon, Washington and Washington D.C.
Biographical Information:
E. Virginia Barnett served as executive director of the University of Houston Foundation until 1987. The University of Houston Foundation raises funds for and promotes the university. There is an UH undergraduate scholarship in her name.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Postcards
Geographic Name:
United States -- Description and travel; United States -- History; United States -- Pictorial works
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains eighty-eight vintage postcards collected by E. Virginia Barnett. The collection includes materials from Arkansas, California, Illinois, New Jersey, New York, Texas, Virginia, Oregon, Washington and Washington D.C. Some items are booklets containing several views of a particular event or locale. The collection is organized by state, and then further subdivided by city.
Detailed List of Contents
- Arkansas
  - Hot Springs
    - Hot Springs National Park, undated (Box 1, Item 1)
      Iron Spring in the "Gorge"
    - Hot Springs National Park, undated (Box 1, Item 2)
      Mirror Lake in "The Gorge"
- California
  - Palomar
    - Palomar Observatory, undated (Box 1, Item 3)
    - Palomar Observatory, Palomar Mountain, undated (Box 1, Item 4)
  - San Francisco
    - Folding Postcard Views of the "Jewel City", 1915 (Box 1, Item 5)
      Panama-Pacific International Exposition
- Illinois
  - Springfield
    - Statue of Abraham Lincoln, undated (Box 1, Item 6)
      by Andrew O'Connor
- New Jersey
  - Atlantic City
    - Absecon Lighthouse, copyright 1900 (Box 1, Item 7)
    - Bathers Early in the Morning, undated (Box 1, Item 8)
    - Boardwalk Scene, undated (Box 1, Item 9)
    - Crowded Boardwalk, undated (Box 1, Item 10)
    - Marlborough-Blenheim, undated (Box 1, Item 11)
    - Sand Artist's Work, undated (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Shelburn Hotel, At Night, undated (Box 1, Item 13)
- New York
  - New York City
    - Aquarium and New York Harbor, undated (Box 1, Item 14)
    - Brooklyn Bridge, the Cables, undated (Box 1, Item 15)
    - City Investing Building, undated (Box 1, Item 16)
    - Ellis Island, undated (Box 1, Item 17)
    - Hotel Astor, undated (Box 1, Item 18)
    - Hudson River Tunnel Curve, undated (Box 1, Item 19)
    - Madison Square, undated (Box 1, Item 20)
    - Madison Square Garden, undated (Box 1, Item 21)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Building, undated (Box 1, Item 22)
    - Saint Paul's Chapel, undated (Box 1, Item 23)
    - Singer Building and Tower, undated (Box 1, Item 24)
    - Trinity Building and Broadway, undated (Box 1, Item 25)
- Texas
  - Austin
    - Aerial View of Austin, Texas, undated (Box 1, Item 25)
      Looking North West, Courthouse in Front of the Capitol
    - Engineering Building, undated (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Galveston
    - In the Surf, Showing Murdoch's Bath House, Seawall and Boulevard, undated (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Houston
    - Auditorium, undated (Box 1, Item 29)
    - Old Bell Captured from the Gun Boat, "Harriet Lane' in City Park, undated (Box 1, Item 30)
    - First National Bank Building, undated (Box 1, Item 31)
    - Hirsch Apartments, undated (Box 1, Item 32)
    - Ivanhoe Apartments, undated (Box 1, Item 33)
  - San Antonio
    - City Hall, undated (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Texarkana
    - Cotton Bell Hospital, undated (Box 1, Item 35)
    - Cotton Compress, undated (Box 1, Item 36)
    - Spring Lake Park, undated (Box 1, Item 37)
      Spring Lake
  - Witchita Falls
    - Woman's Forum, undated (Box 1, Item 38)
- Virginia
  - Arlington
    - Curtis-Lee Mansion, undated (Box 1, Item 39)
- Oregon
  - Portland
    - City Hall, undated (Box 1, Item 40)
    - Buffalo in City Park, undated (Box 1, Item 41)
    - Statue of the "Coming of the White Men" in City Park, undated (Box 1, Item 42)
    - Freight Yards and Union Depot, undated (Box 1, Item 43)
    - Hotel Multnomah, signed 1920 (Box 1, Item 44)
    - North Bank Railway Bridge, undated (Box 1, Item 45)
      (two miles long,) crossing the Columbia River from Vancouver, Washington, to Portland, Oregon.
    - Oregonian Building, approximately 1910 (Box 1, Item 46)
    - Portland Heights, undated (Box 1, Item 47)
    - Portland Hotel, undated (Box 1, Item 48)
- Washington
  - Seattle
    - Capitol Hill and Holy Names Academy, undated (Box 1, Item 49)
    - First Avenue, undated (Box 1, Item 50)
    - High School, undated (Box 1, Item 51)
    - How they cut down hills in Seattle, Washington, undated (Box 1, Item 52)
    - Intersection of Union Street and Third Avenue, undated (Box 1, Item 53)
      showing Federal Building
    - King County Court House, undated (Box 1, Item 54)
    - Oregon-Washington and King Street Stations, undated (Box 1, Item 55)
    - Public Library, undated (Box 1, Item 56)
    - Public Market, undated (Box 1, Item 57)
    - Public Market, at Pike Place, postmarked 1915 (Box 1, Item 58)
    - Second Avenue Looking South, undated (Box 1, Item 59)
    - Third Avenue, undated (Box 1, Item 60)
  - Spokane
    - Hayden Lake, Near Spokane, undated (Box 1, Item 61)
    - Monroe Street Bridge and Falls, undated (Box 1, Item 62)
    - Mount Carleton from Spokane, Washington, undated (Box 1, Item 63)
    - North Channel, Upper Falls, postmarked 1912 (Box 1, Item 64)
    - Riverside Avenue, approximately 1913 (Box 1, Item 65)
    - Bird's Eye View of Spokane, Washington, postmarked 1905 (Box 1, Item 66)
  - Tacoma
    - Buffaloes at Point Defiance Park, tacoma, Washington, postmarked 1907 (Box 1, Item 67)
      Buffalo Calf in Center Four Months Old
    - Cutting a Giant Fir Tree Near Tacoma, Wash., postmarked 1907 (Box 1, Item 68)
    - High School, postmarked 1907 (Box 1, Item 69)
    - Loggers on Puget Sound, postmarked 1917 (Box 1, Item 70)
    - Logging Train, Forests of Washington, postmarked 1907 (Box 1, Item 71)
    - Pacific Avenue, undated (Box 1, Item 72)
- Washington, D.C.
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Corcoran Art Gallery, undated (Box 1, Item 73)
    - Executive Mansion, East Room, undated (Box 1, Item 74)
    - House of Representatives Office Building, undated (Box 1, Item 75)
    - Lafayette Statue, undated (Box 1, Item 76)
    - Library of Congress, undated (Box 1, Item 77)
    - Reading Room, Congressional Library, undated (Box 1, Item 78)
    - Municipal or District Building, undated (Box 1, Item 79)
    - New National Museum, undated (Box 1, Item 80)
    - Post Office, undated (Box 1, Item 81)
    - Thomas Circle, undated (Box 1, Item 82)
    - Union Station, undated (Box 1, Item 83)
    - Waiting Room, Union Station, undated (Box 1, Item 84)
    - U.S. Government Printing Office, undated (Box 1, Item 85)
    - Washington Monument, undated (Box 1, Item 86)
    - White House, undated (Box 1, Item 87)
    - New Entrance to the White House, copyright 1907 (Box 1, Item 88)
      Showing the new addition.
    - White House, undated (Box 1, Item 89)
      View of new entrance showing the new addition. There is an esplanade in the foreground. Photograph.